# **Andrew Cartwright**

Full-Stack Software Engineer in Birmingham, AL, specializing in TypeScript, React, and Node.js. Passionate about Arduino projects and Linux. Enthusiastic mentor who enjoys gardening, cooking, woodworking, hiking, and spending time with pets.

Birmingham, AL andrewlloydcartwright@gmail.com https://atlc.dev https://github.com/atlc

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Covalence,** Remote — *Software Developer / Lead Instructor* (2020 - Present)

Led full-stack web development bootcamp, provided personalized 1-on-1 student mentorship, actively developed and maintained curriculum, and produced public programming tutorials.

## **Hubbard Systems**, Remote — *Devops Engineer* (2019 - 2020)

2019 - 2020

Started DevOps department, automated internal processes, created CI/CD pipelines for a COBOL+Java+Electron/React app, and developed devtools and documentation system.

## **Vincari**, Birmingham — *Software Engineer* (2016 - 2017)

Worked on our legacy EMR application in a rebuild phase, performing both bug fixes and developing new features, including creating a logging and analytics system.

## **Hubbard Systems,** Birmingham — *Application System Analyst* (2015 - 2016)

Provided training and support for our accounting application, and performed Windows, Linux, and MS SQL server administration.

#### **EDUCATION**

## A.S. Mathematics, Jefferson State Community College (2024)

Mu Alpha Theta member & obtained a 3.3 GPA in my math courses, including Cal I, II, Statistics, Differential Equations, & Linear Algebra.

## A.S. CIS - Programming, Jefferson State Community College (2017)

The recipient of the 2016 College Scholars award

## **Additional Academic Achievements**

Completed 152 cumulative credit hours between my healthcare and STEM studies at Jefferson State and Auburn University, exceeding requirements for a Bachelor's degree.

#### **SKILLS**

TypeScript, React, Node.js, ES6+
JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, mobile
responsive design, Tailwind,
Bootstrap, MaterialUI,
styled-components, Stripe, Square,
Mailgun, Mailchimp, auth, Passport.js,
JWTs, RESTful API design, Relational
SQL (mainly Postgres and MySQL),
NoSQL (primarily MongoDB),
key-value DBs (primarily Redis),
python, C++, Arduino, Linux, git, AWS,
Azure, Heroku, DigitalOcean, Devops,
Jenkins

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

### Microsoft:

- Azure Fundamentals
- MTA Software Development
- MTA Database Administration
- MTA Security Fundamentals

#### AWS:

- Certified Cloud Practitioner
- Certified Developer (expected August 2024)

## **Linux Professional Institute:**

- Linux Essentials
- LPIC-1 (expected August 2024)

## CompTIA:

- Healthcare IT Technician